Guide to the Duke Real Estate Office records, 1893-2018 and undated UA.10.04.0007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Real Estate Office records
1893-2018, undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Real Estate Office
UA.10.04.0007
15 Linear Feet
The Duke Real Estate Office manages and makes plans for all space owned by Duke University and Duke University Health System, the Washington Duke Inn, and Duke Forest. The Duke Real Estate Office Records contain copies of deeds; easements; correspondence; maps; real estate documents; and reports of the land transactions for the building of Duke University since acquiring the first lots in 1893; Highland Hospital properties in Buncombe County; Maplewood Cemetery; and Urban Land Institute studies.
Arrangement
The Duke Real Estate Office records are arranged in the following Series: Real Estate Deeds; Real Estate Easements; and Administrative Files.
Biographical / Historical
The Duke Real Estate Office manages and makes plans for all space owned by Duke University and Duke University Health System, the Washington Duke Inn, and Duke Forest. The Duke Real Estate Office oversees more than 200 leases covering approximately 2.5 million square feet of office, medical, clinic, laboratory, warehouse space, and the approximate 7,000 acres of the Duke Forest. The Duke Real Estate Office is grouped with the Financial Department under the Office of the Executive Vice President.
The Duke Real Estate Office receives and tracks deeds of gifted property from wills or estate planning which have included donors' principal residences or vacation homes, farms, commercial buildings, subdivision lots or unimproved land, and would manage sales of these properties. The Duke Real Estate Office managed properties including Highland Hospital in Asheville, and Maplewood Cemetery in Durham. Note also that many of the deeds are for properties in Duke Forest that were sold to faculty and staff.
Duke University dates its origin as an educational institution from 1838, when Methodist and Quaker families in rural Randolph County hired Brantley York as a teacher for their school. York's successor as principal, Braxton Craven (president 1842-1882), encouraged the North Carolina legislature to recharter the school as Normal College in 1851. The school was renamed Trinity College in 1859, while funded by the Methodist Episcopal Church, South. John F. Crowell became Trinity's president in 1887. Using funding from Washington Duke and Julian S. Carr, the school moved to Durham in 1892.
In December 1924, James B. Duke increased his family's support of Trinity College with the establishment of The Duke Endowment, a $40-million trust fund. Along with annual income distributed to Carolinian hospitals, orphanages, the Methodist Church, $19 million was directed to three colleges and a university built around Trinity College. The funds were earmarked for rebuilding the old campus, and for creation of a new campus. President Few suggested the school be called Duke University, which then opened the School of Religion and Graduate School (1926); the Medical School and hospital (1930); the School of Nursing (1931); and the School of Forestry (1938); and reorganized the Law School (1930). In 1938, Duke University became the thirty-fourth member of the Association of American Universities. Later Engineering became a separate school (1939); and the School of Business Administration, now the Fuqua School of Business, opened in 1969.
The City of Durham's Maplewood Cemetery was established in 1872. Residents buried there include Dr. Bartlett Durham. Members of the Washington Duke family are interred in the Duke Mausoleum. While Washington Duke, and sons Benjamin Newton Duke and James Buchanan Duke, were re-interred in the Chapel of Duke University, the tomb still contains the remains of eldest son Brodie Duke and several women of the Duke family, including philanthropist Mary Duke Biddle.
Access Restrictions
Deeds in the Duke Real Estate Office records are copies of public records, and are open for research. Any additional materials filed with the deeds that are Duke University administrative records are restricted for a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, in which case permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, administrative records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist. Contact Research Services for more information.
Provenance
The Duke Real Estate Office records were received by Duke University Archives as a transfer in 2019.
Related Materials
Property Plats.
University Archives, Duke University.
Facilities Management Department records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The Duke Real Estate Office records contain copies of deeds; maps; related correspondence; and reports of the land transactions for the building of Duke University since acquiring the first lots in 1893.
Real estate management -- North Carolina; Real property -- North Carolina; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- History; Duke family; Duke Forest (N.C.); Duke University. -- Marine Laboratory; Highland Hospital (Asheville, N.C.); Urban Land Institute; Duke family; Duke Forest (Durham, N.C.); Duke University. Marine Laboratory; Highland Hospital, Asheville, N.C.; Durham County (N.C.); Urban Land Institute
- Real Estate Deeds, 1893-2018; undated
  Conditions Governing Access
  Deeds in the Real Estate Office are copies of public records, and are open for research. Any additional materials filed with the deeds that are Duke University administrative records are restricted for a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, in which case permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, administrative records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist. Contact Research Services for more information.
  - File No.: 1, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: T. W. Snipes, Type: Deed, 1925 March 5 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 2, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. D. Wheeler, Type: Deed, 1925 March 6 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 601, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 34, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: 2 Tracts (Rigsbee Road)Between 33&34, 5.35+1 ac
  - File No.: 3, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. J. Durham, Type: Deed, 1925 March 5 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 591, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 15, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Erwin Road, 15.52 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 4, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. K. Watkins, Type: Deed, 1925 March 5 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 600, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 35, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Rigsbee Road, 5.23 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 5, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: R. E. Paschall, Type: Deed, 1925 March 9 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 607, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 3, Sec 2, PB 6/2, Comments/Location: N/S Cornwallis Road, 42.76 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 6, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: T. D. & R. H. Wright, Type: Deed, 1925 March 9 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 603, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 101, 158-161, Comments/Location: Around Lakewood Park Place, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 7, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Charles Pickett, Type: Deed, 1925 March 4 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 599, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 7, Sec 2, PB 6/2, Comments/Location: N/S Cornwallis Road, 108.86 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 8, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: S.A.W. Fitzgerald, Type: Deed, 1925 March 6 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 629, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 6, Sec 2, PB 6/2, Comments/Location: N Cornwallis Road, 68.4 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 9, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. M. Ladd, Type: Deed, 1925 March 9 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 604, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 10, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N/S Rigsbee Road, 13.8 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 10, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. G. Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 March 9 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 606, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 30.5, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S Rigsbee Road, 26.33 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 11, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. G. Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 April 16 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 187, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 30, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S Rigsbee Road, 13 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 12, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: E. C. Pendergrass, Type: Deed, 1925 March 10 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 612, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 45, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Rigsbee Rd at Mud Creek, 49.69 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 13, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: H. M. Browning, Type: Deed, 1925 March 11 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 628, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 16, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: SS/Erwin Road, 5 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 14, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. A. Tillman, Type: Deed, 1925 March 11 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 646, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 48, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: W/S Cornwallis Road, 23.85 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 15, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: B. O. Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 49, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 31, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Rigsbee Road, 177.65 ac (Burying Ground 1/4 ac), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 16, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: 1st Nat'l Bank/Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 March 28 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 72, Page: 611, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 20,26,27, Sec 1 PB 6/1, Comments/Location: 3 Tracts/Rigsbee Road, 150.3, 34.63, 37.1 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-A, 17
  - File No.: 17, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: H. V. Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 72, Page: 613, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 20, 26, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: 2 Tracts/Rigsbee Road, 150.3, 34.63 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-A, 16
  - File No.: 18, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. P. Smith, Type: Deed, 1925 March 25 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 56, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 50, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N Cornwallis Road, 15.12 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A, 16
  - File No.: 19, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. T. Burroughs, Type: Deed, 1925 March 30 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 79, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 43, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Rigsbee Road, 90 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 20, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. H. Couch, Type: Deed, 1925 March 25 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 67, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 33, 37, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: 2 Tracts S/S Rigsbee Road, 5.4, 5.72 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 21, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: T. E. Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 March 28 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 112, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 44, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Rigsbee Road, 31.1 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 22, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Erwin Cotton Mills, Type: Deed, 1925 April 4 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 77, Page: 62, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 23, 26.5, 2&3, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: 3 Tracts/Anderson St./Erwin Road, Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 23, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Erwin Cotton Mills, Type: Deed, 1925 April 30 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 63, Deed Book: 77, Page: 73, Map-Block-Lot: Part/Lot 23, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: Erwin Avenue, Old/New File No.: 2
  - File No.: 24, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: C. D. Hall, Type: Deed, 1925 March 28 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 149, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 17, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: Erwin Road, 2.56 ac (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-A
  - File No.: 25, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: M. H. Turner, Type: Deed, 1925 April 27 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 74, Deed Book: 244, Page: Lot 52, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Map-Block-Lot: S Rigsbee Road, 65.5 ac, Comments/Location: 1-A, Old/New File No.: includes one unnumbered
  - File No.: 26, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. D. Davis, Type: Deed, 1925 February 4 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 426, Map-Block-Lot: Part of Tract 4, PB 1/180, Comments/Location: Stagg Farm, J.Q. Davis Property, 15.6 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 27, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: T. M. Davis, Type: Deed, 1925 January 24 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 427, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 25, Sec. 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: W/ Anderson Street, 0.95 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 28, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: T. M. Davis, Type: Deed, 1925 February 10 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 532, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 8, 10, PB 5/146, Comments/Location: 3 Tracts, (30 Ft. Roadway) Davis Property, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 29, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: A. E. Barefoot, Type: Deed, 1925 March 11 (Box 1)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 656, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 14, Sec. 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/Erwin Road, 6.6 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 30, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. M. Nissen, Type: Deed, 1925 January 31 (Box 2)
    County: Orange, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 72, Page: 426, Map-Block-Lot: PB M/460, Comments/Location: Annie Patterson, Orange Co, 10/25/05, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 31, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. R. Vickers, Type: Deed, 1925 February 4 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 424, Map-Block-Lot: Tracts 8, 9, PB 3/186, Comments/Location: Rigsbee Road/Davis Farm, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 32, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: H. E. Rodenhizer, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 551, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 40, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/Rigsbee Road, 4.43 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 33, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: R. H. Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 556, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 28, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/Rigsbee Road, 11.61 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 34, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: R. H. Rigsbee, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 557, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 29, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/Rigsbee Road, 13.07 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 35, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. L. Foushee, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 548, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 11,32, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N&SS/Rigsbee Road, 92.36 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 36, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. L. Foushee, Type: Deed, 1925 March 23 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 47, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 7, Sec 3, PB 6/2, Comments/Location: S/S Rigsbee Road, 178.1 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 37, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. L. Foushee, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 48, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 53, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N/S Cornwallis Road, 93.83 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-B
  - File No.: 38, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: L. W. Overby, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 572, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 13, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Erwin Road, 39.4 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 39, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: O. H. Pickett, Type: Deed, 1925 March 2 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 571, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 2, Sec 2, PB 6/2, Comments/Location: N/S Cornwallis Road, 70.06 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 40, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J.M. Shepherd, Type: Deed, 1925 March 5 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 586, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 46,47, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: Cornwallis Road, Rigsbee Road, 2.44 +17.5 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 41, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Frank Cook, Type: Deed, 1925 March 3 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 562, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 9, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N/S Rigsbee Road, 7.02 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 42, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: M. P. Harrell, Type: Deed, 1925 March 3 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 555, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 49, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: E/S Cornwallis Road, 41.6 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 43, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: A. M. Cook, Type: Deed, 1925 March 3 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 566, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 6,8, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: 2 Tracts/Rigsbee Road, 6.64 +24.54 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 44, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. M. Hunt, Type: Deed, 1925 March 4 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 565, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 4, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N/S Rigsbee Road, 8.01 ac, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 45, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: H. W. Pickett, Type: Deed, 1925 March 9 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 605, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 4, Sec 2, PB 6/2, Comments/Location: N/S Cornwallis Road, 62.52 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 46, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: C. J. Clark, Type: Deed, 1925 March 5 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 585, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 7, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N/S Rigsbee Road, 5.98 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 47, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. T. Turner, Type: Deed, 1925 April 10 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 155, Map-Block-Lot: DU\Rice Boundary, 2/19/33, Comments/Location: Chapel Hill Boulevard, 1.1 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 48, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Richard Pickett, Type: Deed, 1925 March 28 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 153, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 1 Sec 2, PB 6/2, Comments/Location: N\S Cornwallis Road, 95.5 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 49, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. L. Morehead, Trustee, Type: Deed, 1925 April 14 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 72, Page: 668, Map-Block-Lot: PB 2/162, Comments/Location: Chapel Hill Boulevard, 4.8 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 50, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. A. Erwin, Jr., Type: Deed, 1925 April 30 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 63, Deed Book: 74, Page: 287, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 1, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: E/S Erwin & Rigsbee Roads, 14.3 acs, Old/New File No.: 2
  - File No.: 51, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: J. R. Turnage, Type: Deed, 1925 April 20 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 74, Page: 284, Map-Block-Lot: Lts 18, 21, 22, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: 3 tracts/Erwin Road Area, 5.3 +1.5+1.41 acs, Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 52, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: D. R. Shipp, Type: Deed, 1925 April 18 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 63, Deed Book: 74, Page: 222, Map-Block-Lot: Lts 1,2,6,PB 5/185, Comments/Location: 3 Tracts Rigsbee Road, Shipp Property, 15.1 acs, Old/New File No.: 2
  - File No.: 53, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: W. A. Fulford, Type: Deed, 1925 February 25 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 62, Deed Book: 73, Page: 563, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 36, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: S/S Rigsbee Road, 5.7 acs (Forest), Old/New File No.: 1-C
  - File No.: 54, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Fred Burroughs, Type: Deed, 1925 April 20 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 63, Deed Book: 74, Page: 246, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 51.5, Sec 1, PB 6/1, Comments/Location: N/S Cornwallis Road, 2.57 acs, Old/New File No.: 2
  - File No.: 55, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: C. N. Parker, Type: Deed, 1925 April 11 (Box 2)
    County: Orange, Conveyed by File No.: 116, Deed Book: 86, Page: 7, Comments/Location: State Highway #10 (104 Acres)
  - File No.: 56, Grantee: Duke, Grantor: C. N. Parker, Type: Deed, 1925 May 21 (Box 2)
    County: Orange, Conveyed by File No.: 116, Deed Book: 85, Page: 174, Comments/Location: Around Eno River Area
  - File No.: 57, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Cornelius Brown, Type: Deed, 1925 April 22 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 178, Deed Book: 74, Page: 503, Comments/Location: 7.17 acres, Plat 6, Page 1
  - File No.: 58, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: C. W. Pickett, Type: Deed, 1925 April 9 (Box 2)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 335, Deed Book: 129, Page: 131, Comments/Location: Cornwallis Road
  - File No.: 59, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: P. L. Clayton, Type: Deed, 1925 March 31 (Box 2)
    County: Orange, Conveyed by File No.: 116, Deed Book: 85, Page: 94, Comments/Location: Old Greensboro Road
  - File No.: 60, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Tom Walker, Type: Deed, 1925 April 2 (Box 2)
    County: Orange, Conveyed by File No.: 116, Deed Book: 82, Page: 603, Comments/Location: Conveyance of Rock
  - File No.: 61, Grantee: Murray Jones, Grantor: Fannie Mayo, Type: Deed, 1925 March 12 (Box 3)
    County: Orange, Conveyed by File No.: 116, Deed Book: 82, Page: 600, Comments/Location: Conveyance of Rock
  - File No.: 62, Grantee: Duke, Grantor: Murray Jones, Type: Deed, 1925 April 24 (Box 3)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 77, Page: 64, Comments/Location: Tracts 1-63, ref: 1, 22-24, 49-51, Old/New File No.: 1
  - File No.: 63, Grantee: Duke, Grantor: Murray Jones, Type: Deed, 1925 April 30 (Box 3)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 77, Page: 74, Comments/Location: 4 tracts of land
  - File No.: 64, Grantee: First National Trust Co., Grantor: James D. Davis, Type: Deed, 1924 December 27 (Box 3)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 113, Deed Book: 73, Page: 274, Comments/Location: 3 lots - Washington Street
  - File No.: 65, Grantee: First National Trust Co., Grantor: Sallie Bynum, Type: Deed, 1925 July 29 (Box 3)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 115, Deed Book: 78, Page: 181, Comments/Location: Powe Street
  - File No.: 66, Grantee: First National Trust Co., Grantor: Sallie Bynum, Type: Deed, 1925 September 23 (Box 3)
    County: Durham, Conveyed by File No.: 115, Deed Book: 78, Page: 474, Comments/Location: Powe Street